siteadvisor.com 2010-12-31

# Antivirus Software and Internet Security For Your PC | McAfee

Print 

**As the world's largest dedicated security provider, McAfee understands the importance of protecting personal information. This privacy policy outlines how McAfee collects, uses, and discloses your personal information. You will also find information on how you can update your account and preferences, as well as details on how we protect your personal information.**

  1. Why does McAfee gather personal information?
  2. What information does McAfee collect and how is it used?
  3. Does McAfee disclose personal information?
  4. How does McAfee secure personal information?
  5. Remember—information displayed to the public is not secure.
  6. Can you control how your information is used?
  7. What privacy policy applies if you follow a link on McAfee's website?
  8. Can you review and update the personal information that McAfee collects?
  9. Does McAfee keep track of website visitor data?
  10. Does McAfee comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act?
  11. Additional information for users in the European Economic Area (EEA)
  12. How often does McAfee update its privacy policy?
  13. Contact us

  1. #### Why does McAfee gather personal information?

McAfee gathers personal information in order to provide the award-winning products, service, and support you've come to expect from us. As with most transactions, personal information is required in order to set up your account and complete your purchase. But it also helps us provide the product and support information we believe is of greatest interest to you. 

  2. #### What information does McAfee collect and how is it used?

There are a variety of situations in which McAfee may collect personal information, such as when you register as a customer; purchase one of our products; download free evaluation software, upgrades, or white papers; order email newsletters; respond to a marketing campaign; place orders on our website; or when you're working with a McAfee service representative. In each of those situations, McAfee only collects the personal information required to meet your needs. Depending on the circumstances, we may ask for your name, company name, Internet domain name, industry, IP address, billing or shipping address, credit card information, email address, fax number, phone number, or other pertinent information.

McAfee uses your information to better understand your needs, provide you with the services you have requested, and with a view to provide you with better service. We may use your information to help you complete a transaction, (including fulfillment of orders and promotional offers), to communicate back to you, to inform you of and update you on services and benefits, and to manage and renew your subscription(s). Credit card numbers are used only for payment processing, maintenance of your subscription, including renewals, and fraud protection and are not used for other purposes without your permission. McAfee will keep your personal information for as long as you are a registered subscriber or user of our product(s) and thereafter, for no longer than is reasonably necessary for internal reporting and reconciliation purposes and to provide you with any feedback or information that you might request or require.

With the consent of our customers, McAfee posts customer testimonials on our website, which may contain personally identifiable information, such as the customer's name.

If at any time you wish to remove your personal information from a McAfee website testimonial, please contact [customer service](http://service.mcafee.com/CustomerService.aspx?lc=1033&sg=CS&pt=1).

  3. #### Does McAfee disclose personal information?

In limited circumstances, McAfee may need to share your information in order to meet your particular needs. McAfee has a number of relationships with vendors with whom we may share your personal information for the purpose of providing a service, fulfilling an order, or meeting your other needs, including the provision of customer support. For example, we use selected vendors for the purpose of providing credit card transaction and check processing services. These vendors verify your purchase information, such as credit card number or checking account number, and authorize your transaction. In doing so, the vendors have access to limited information about users, but they are prohibited from using the information for any other purpose. McAfee imposes strict confidentiality obligations on all third-party vendors with whom we share your information. By providing your information to us, you are deemed to consent to the transfer of your information to McAfee's third-party vendors in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

We may also need to share your personal information with other legal entities within McAfee. All such entities adhere to the McAfee Privacy Policy. From time to time, McAfee may provide personal information to law enforcement authorities or other third parties in response to a subpoena, an official inquiry, or as may be required in the case of national security. McAfee will not disclose your personal information to third parties for their own marketing purposes unless you have provided prior consent.

Digital River is a third-party vendor providing e-commerce solutions for McAfee's online stores. As a result, McAfee shares certain personal information with Digital River to complete your transactions. The protection of such information is addressed in Digital River's [Privacy Statement](http://www.digitalriver.com/corporate/privacy.shtml). McAfee disclaims all liability for the data processing activities of its outside vendors. If you do not wish to have your credit card number stored, please contact [customer service](http://service.mcafee.com/CustomerService.aspx?lc=1033&sg=CS&pt=1).

  4. #### How does McAfee secure personal information?

McAfee uses state-of-the-art security technology to protect our customer data. Access to customer information is restricted to authorized personnel only. Our website is regularly tested for security vulnerabilities to ensure all collected information is secure from unauthorized viewing. Personal customer information is protected in transit via HTTPS and SSL security. Credit card information is transmitted with multiple layers of security, including encryption in storage and SSL in transit. For more information, please review the section on disclosure of information above.

McAfee complies with PCI Data Security Standards that require merchants to implement strong security measures to protect our customers' credit card information.

McAfee shall notify you in the unlikely event of a security breach involving your personal data.

  5. #### Remember—information displayed to the public is not secure.

Please remember that the information you submit in discussion groups or forums will be deemed public information and will not be kept as confidential. There is a risk that the information posted in these discussion groups or forums will be collected and used by others. Please be careful and responsible when you are participating in any discussion groups or forums on the McAfee website(s).

  6. #### Can you control how your information is used?

Yes. As mentioned above, McAfee may use your information to improve the content of our website, products, and services, or to alert you to information we believe might interest you. When you register or make a purchase, we offer you the opportunity to opt into or out of these uses of your information. If you do not choose to opt out initially, you may still block future contact of this type by simply following the unsubscribe instructions that accompany all such communications, contacting [customer service](http://service.mcafee.com/CustomerService.aspx?lc=1033&sg=CS&pt=1), or visiting the [My Account section](http://home.mcafee.com/root/MyAccount.aspx) on our website.

Please note that we do not allow our customers to opt out of content that is essential to the functionality of our products and services, such as communications relating to necessary updates to our products.

  7. #### What privacy policy applies if you follow a link on McAfee's website?

Our site contains links to other websites. If you follow one of those links, you may be leaving McAfee's website and entering a site not under McAfee's control. McAfee does not accept liability for misuse of any information submitted on any site outside its control. We strongly encourage you to read the privacy statements or policies of the linked sites, as their privacy policies may differ from ours.

  8. #### Can you review and update the personal information that McAfee collects?

Yes. Users can access and update most of the personal information that McAfee holds by visiting the [My Account](http://home.mcafee.com/root/MyAccount.aspx) section for our Home and Home Office products, by visiting the online portal for the software-as-a-service products(s) you are using, or by contacting [customer service](http://service.mcafee.com/CustomerService.aspx?lc=1033&sg=CS&pt=1).

  9. #### Does McAfee keep track of website visitor data?

**Cookies**

Like many other companies, McAfee uses "cookies" to remember user preferences and maximize performance of our website and services. Cookies are alphanumeric identifiers that McAfee transfers to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser. This allows McAfee to recognize your browser and identify you as a returning user to the McAfee website so that, for example, we don't need to ask you to enter your email and password on every visit.

Cookies may also be used to control the type and/or frequency of ads, promotions, or other marketing messages that you view on our website. These ads may be placed by third-party advertising companies. Any information the advertising companies collect is non-personal and anonymous.

It is possible to prevent your browser from accepting new cookies or to disable cookies altogether. The Help Menu on the menu bar of most browsers will tell you how to do this. Similar data used by browser "add-ons", such as Flash cookies can also be deleted or disabled by changing the settings of the add-on. Further information can be obtained by visiting the website of the add-on manufacturer.

Please note the information gathered by cookies is necessary to provide certain essential subscription services to you. We cannot provide those services if you set your browser to reject our cookies. For that reason we recommend that you leave them turned on, but please remember to sign out when you finish using a shared computer.

Any personal information we collect with cookies is not shared with any outside parties.

**Other Website Data**

McAfee also uses "web beacons" (small transparent image files) to count visitors to our sites and analyze how visitors use our sites. The information collected is generally anonymized and is not used to identify any particular user.

As is common on the Internet, McAfee maintains log files of the traffic that visits our sites. For example, our servers may automatically record the information you or your browser send when you visit a website. These log files may include information such as your requests, IP address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request, and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your system.

  10. #### Does McAfee comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act?

Yes. McAfee complies with all the regulations of the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of the United States of America. McAfee does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn we have collected personal information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that data from our systems.

  11. #### Additional information for users in the European Economic Area (EEA)

Our customers' personal information is stored on our servers currently located in the United States. The location of our servers may be subject to change.

In addition, McAfee may transfer your personal information to our vendors outside of the EEA, as described in this privacy policy.

At present, the laws of the United States and other countries outside the EEA (except for Argentina, Canada, Isle of Man, Guernsey, and Switzerland) have not been approved by the European Commission as providing "adequate protection" for personal information within the meaning of the EU Data Protection Directive (95/46/EC).

McAfee imposes strict requirements on our vendors outside of the EEA regarding the use and protection of our customers' personal information. In addition, with regard to our consumer customers, McAfee abides by the Safe Harbor Framework set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information collected from the European Union.

By purchasing or using our products from a country in the EEA and submitting your personal information to us, we deem that you are consenting to the processing of your personal information in the United States or other country outside of the EEA.

  12. #### How often does McAfee update its privacy policy?

We may update this policy at any time by posting additions or modifications on this web page. If at any point we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner materially different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by email or via a prominent notice on our website and where necessary we will seek the prior consent of our users.

  13. #### Contact us

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please contact us using the web form available here.

This privacy policy was last modified on 31/08/2010.
